GARETH BRANDWOOD

Curriculum Vitae

Email: gareth.br@ndwood.uk 119 Powder Mill Road, Warrington, WA4 1GB Mobile: +44 (0)7711 59 10 85

PERSONAL PROFILE

I have obtained substantial expertise working in professional and technical roles for over 20 years; successfully managing IT business services and delivering *positive change* as part of system/application development. Whilst I am comfortable working independently, my preference is to work with talented individuals, crafting successful teams by leading and facilitating, always with a focus on delivery.

My best quality is my ability to adapt and acquire new skills, which has supported the various roles I have carried out in my career to-date. For example, my recent MBA dissertation, 'Expanding Perspectives on Project Management', drew upon these skills to present recommendations on how best to evaluate the success of project delivery.

In my precious spare time, I occasionally manage to enjoy the theatre and work on my game of badminton.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

University of Chester Master of Business Administration (MBA) – Distinction	2015 – 2018
University of Liverpool/Institute of Leadership and Management Leadership – QC5 Level 5 - Pass	2012
QA Limited, Manchester Management of Risk Practitioner	2011
QA Limited, Manchester PRINCE2 Practitioner (2009 Edition) ITIL: Service Design, ITIL: Service Strategy, ITIL: V2 - V3 Bridge	2009/2010
Xpertise Training Limited, University of Liverpool ISEB Certificate in Modelling Business Processes	2008
QA Limited, Manchester ITIL: Practitioner in Change Management, ITIL: Foundation (V2)	2007
CITI Limited, University of Liverpool CITI Project Management	2006
Chester City Council ECDL & ECDL Advanced ("ECDL Expert" status)	2005
QA Limited, Manchester Microsoft ADO .net, Microsoft VB.net and Microsoft ASP.net	2004
Newcastle College (Distance Learning) Diploma in Business Coaching	2003
CG Resources, Manchester Microsoft Project 2000	2002
Liverpool John Moores University Bachelor of Arts (Honours) in Business Studies (1st Class Honours)	1997 – 2001
Halton College of Further Education G.N.V.Q. Advanced Business (Distinction – 18 units), A-Level Sociology (grade A)	1995 – 1997
Norton Priory County High School G.C.S.E.s (2 x A* (English & Business Studies), 6 x A grade and 2 x B grade)	1990 – 1995

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Warrington Borough Council Technical Delivery Manager, Transformation (fixed term) June 2018 to present

Reporting to the Head of ICT, Head of Transformation and the Programme Manager, my role has been to facilitate the technical delivery of the digital transformation programme, a multi-million investment in order to make savings of \pounds 5m over 5 years. This involves leading on technical matters for all of the products being worked on by four agile development squads.

I engage with Business Process Owners and work across the agile team, with Senior BAs, our Scrum Master and the Test Lead. I also work closely with the Developers and act as the conduit between the Transformation programme and the BAU Technical Support teams, leading on technical and business readiness activities, to ensure products are fit-for-purpose (MVP).

Products delivered so far include integrations with SAP, various HR process automations and a bespoke e-Recruitment system (for release in April). The platform is cloud-based and I manage the relationship with the external supplier, according to our tendered contract.

All releases go through our standard process for agile software development, using Jira to manage the Scrum boards and backlog. In addition to daily stand-ups, I ensure sprints are preceded by '3 Amigos' sessions and pre-sprint planning and sizing sessions. I check that inputs to these sessions are prepared to a 'good enough' quality (user stories, form flows etc.), and help to remove blockers and facilitate reviews and retrospectives.

Key technologies/skills: Jira, Agile (Scrum), PRINCE2, ITIL, AD, Server 2016, Project, Visio

University of Chester

Sept 2012 to May2018

Information Systems Manager, Learning and Information Services

Reporting to the Director of LIS, managing complex software development projects, looking to maximise the effective use of extant business systems and associated services. The University spans multiple sites across the North West and in line with its growth, I was instrumental in ensuring application functionality met changing requirements.

With a highly-skilled team ('Business Improvement Services') consisting of developers, analysts and testers, I utilised our combined talents, in collaboration with other teams, to ensure our overall capability continued to improve, enabling us to meet the ever-increasing demands placed upon our services and the applications we maintained.

I was accountable for the delivery of all development projects in the team, with projects that varied in size and scope – from internal bespoke developments using waterfall and agile methods, to acquiring and implementing tailored COTS systems. For example, I lead on the introduction of the health and social care 'InPlace' system, which was a large-scale project, procured and implemented by a consortium of universities.

Key technologies/skills: MS Office, Project, Visio, SharePoint, Dynamics CRM, MS/MySQL, PHP, PRINCE2, ITIL

University of Liverpool Systems Manager, Facilities Management

Jan 2006 to Sept 2012

Reporting to the Head of Strategy and Business Services, I managed a team of staff dedicated to improving the systems infrastructure in the Facilities Management department.

With the responsibility for multiple software project budgets, some in excess of £700k per project, I shaped the system processes for the department, liaising with other university technical teams and stakeholder groups to solve complex and sometimes highly political and sensitive issues.

The Planon Workplace Management solution was one such project which replaced a number of siloed systems with a single, integrated, facilities management information system. I managed the relationship with the supplier from contract signing to BAU.

Key technologies/skills: PRINCE2, ITIL, Oracle PL/SQL, VBA

Chester City Council
Analyst Programmer, e-Government and Technology

Mar 2004 to Jan 2006

Key technologies/skills: ASP.net, VB.net, Microsoft Access, MS SQL

Central Manchester & Manchester Children's University Hospitals NHS Trust Jul 2001 to Feb 2004 Web Manager, Information Management & Technology Directorate